Wonder by RJ palaso apples MY BIRTHDAY IS October 10th I like my birthday 1010 It would
have been great if I’d been born at exactly 10:::10 in the morning or at night,
but I wasn’t. I was born just after midnight. But I still think my birthday
is cool. I usually have a little party at
home, but this year I ask Mom Mom if I could have a big bowling party. Mom was
surprised but happy. She asked me who I wanted to ask for my class, and I said
everyone in my home room plus Summer.
“That’s a lot of kids, Auggie,” said Mom. “I have to invite everyone because I don’t
want anyone to get their feelings hurt if they find out other people are
invited and they aren’t, okay?” “Okay,” Mom agreed. “You even want to
invite the ‘what’s the deal’ kid?” “Yeah, you can invite Julian,” I answered.
“Geez, Mom, you should forget about that already.” “I know, you’re right.” A couple of
weeks later, I asked Mom who was coming to my party, and she said: “Jack Will,
Summer Reed Kingsley. Both Max's And a couple of other kids said they were
going to try to be there.” “Like who?” “Charlotte’s mom said Charlotte had a
dance recital earlier in the day day, but she was going to try to come to your
party if time allowed. And Tristan’s mom said he might come after his soccer game.”
“So that’s it I said. “That’s like five people.” “That’s more than five people,
Auggie. I think a lot of people just had plans already,” Mom answered. We were in
the kitchen. She was cutting one of the apples we had just gotten at the farmers’
market into Teensy wey bites so I could eat it. “What kind of plans?” I asked.
“I don’t know, Auggie. We sent out the evites kind of late.” “Like what did they
tell you, though? What reasons did they give?” “Everyone gave different reasons,
Auggie.” She sounded a bit impatient.
“Really, sweetie, it shouldn’t matter what their reasons were. People had plans,
that’s all.” “What did Julian give as his reason?” I asked. “You know,” said Mom, “his mom
was the only person who didn’t RSVP at all.” She looked at me. “I guess the apple
doesn’t fall far from the tree.” I laughed because I thought she was making a joke
then I realized she wasn’t. “What does that mean?” I asked. “Never mind. Now go wash
your hands so you can eat.” My birthday party turned out to be much smaller than
I thought it would be, but it was still great. Jack, Summer Reed Tristan, and both
Max's came from school, and Christopher came, too— —all the way from Bridgeport
with his parents. And Uncle Ben came. And Aunt Kate and Uncle Po drove in from
Boston, though Tata and papa were in Florida for the winter. It was fun
because all the grown-ups ended up bullying in the lane next to ours, so it
really felt like there were a lot of people there to celebrate my
birthday Halloween AT LUNCH THE next day, Summer asked me what I was going to be
for Halloween. Of course, I’d been thinking about it since last Halloween,
so I knew right away OA Fett.” “You know you can wear a costume to school on
Halloween, right?” “No way, really?” “So as long as it’s politically correct.” “What, like no
guns and stuff?” “Exactly.” “What about blasters?” “I think a blaster is like a gun,
Auggie.” “Oh man I said, shaking my head.
Boba Fett has a blaster. “At least, we don’t have to come
like a character in a book anymore. In the lower school that’s what you had to
do. Last year I was the Wicked Witch of the West from The Wizard of Oz “But
that’s a movie, not a book.” “Hello?” Summer answered. “It was a book first! One of my
favorite books in the world, actually. My dad used to read it to me every night in
the first grade.” When Summer talks, especially when she’s excited about something, her eyes
squint like she’s looking right at the sun. I hardly ever see Summer during
during the day, since the only class we have together is English. But ever since
that first lunch at school, we’ve set at the summer table together every day, just
the two of us. “So, what are you going to
be?” I asked her. “I don’t know yet. I know
what I’d really want to go as, but I think it might be too dorky. You know
Savannah's group isn’t even wearing costumes this year. They think we’re too
old for Halloween.” “What? That’s just dumb.” “I know, right?” “I thought you didn’t care
what those girls think.” She shrugged and took a long drink of her milk. “So, what
dorky thing do you want to dress up as?” I asked her, smiling. “Promise not to laugh?”
She raised her eyebrows and her shoulders, embarrassed. “A
unicorn.” I smiled and looked down at my sandwich. “Hey, you promise not to laugh!”
she laughed. “Okay, okay,” I said. “But you’re right: that is too
dorky.” “I know!” she said. “But I have it all
planned out: I’d make the head out of papier-mâââché,é and paint the horn gold and
make the main gold, too. It would be so awesome.” “Okay.” I shrugged. “Then you should
do it. Who cares what other people think, right?” “Maybe what I’ll do is just wear it
for the Halloween Parade,” she said Snapp snapping her fingers. “And I’ll just be,
like, a Goth girl for school. Yeah, that’s
it, that’s what I’ll do.” “Sounds like a plan.” I nodded. “Thanks Augie she giggled.
“You know, that’s what I like best about you. I feel like I can tell you anything.”
“Yeah?” I answered, nodding. I gave her a thumbs up sign. “Cool
beans school pictures I DON’T THINK anyone would be shocked to learn I don’t
want to have my school picture taken on October 22nd No way. No thank you. I stopped
letting anyone take pictures of me a while ago. I guess you could call it a
phobia. No, actually, it’s not a phobia.
It’s an “aversion,” which is a word I just learned in Mr Brown's class. I have an
aversion to having my picture taken.
There, I used it in a sentence. I thought Mom would try to get me to drop my
aversion to having my picture taken for school, but she didn’t. Unfortunately,
while I managed to avoid having the portrait taken, I couldn’t get out of
being part of the class picture ug The photographer looked like he just sucked
on a lemon when he saw me. I’m sure he
thought I ruined the picture. I was one of the ones in the front, sitting down. I
didn’t smile, not that anyone could tell if I had
the Cheese Touch I NOTICED NOT too long ago that even though people were getting
used to me, no one would actually touch me. I didn’t realize this at first
because it’s not like kids go around touching each other that much in middle
school anyway. But last Thursday in dance class, which is, like, my least favorite
class, Mrs anabi the teacher, tried to make zenima Chin be my dance partner. Now,
I’ve never actually seen someone have a “panic attack” before, but I have heard
about it, and I’m pretty sure Zima had a panic attack at that second. She got
really nervous and turned pale and literally broke into a sweat within a
minute, and then she came up with some lame excuse about really having to go to
the bathroom. Anyway, Mrs anatomi let her off the hook, because she ended up not
making anyone dance together. Then yesterday in my science elective, we were
doing this cool mystery powder investigation where we had to classify a
substance as an acid or a base. Everyone had to heat their mystery powers on a
heating plate and make observations, so we were all huddled around the powders
with our notebooks. Now, there are eight kids in the elective, and seven of them
were squished together on one side of the plate while one of them— —me— —had loads
of room on the other side. So of course I noticed this, but I was hoping Miss Ruben
wouldn’t notice this, because I didn’t want her to say something. But of course
she did notice this, and of course she said something. “Guys, there’s plenty of
room on that side. Tristan, Nino, go over there,” she said, so Tristan and Nino
scooted over to my side. Tristan and Nino have always been okay nice to me. I want
to go on record is saying that. Not super nice like they go out of their way to
hang out with me, but okay nice like they say hello to me and talk to me like
normal. And they didn’t even make a face when Mrs Rubin told them to come on my
side, which a lot of kids do when they think I’m not looking. Anyway, everything
was going fine until Tristan’s mystery powder started melting. He moved his foil
off the plate just as my powder began to melt, too, which is why I went to move
mine off the plate, and then my hand accidentally bumped his hand for a
fraction of a second. Tristan jerked his hand away so fast he dropped his foil on
the floor while also knocking everyone else’s foil off the heating
plate. “Tristan!” yelled Miss rubben but Tristan didn’t even care about the
spilled powder on the floor or that he ruined the experiment. What he was most
concerned about was getting to the lab sink to wash his hands as fast as
possible. That’s when I knew for sure that there was this thing about touching
me at Beacher Prep. I think it’s like the
Cheese Touch in Diary of a Wimpy Kid The kids in that story were afraid they
catch the cooties if they touch the old moldy cheese on the basketball court. At
beater Prep, I’m the old moldy
[Music]
cheese costumes FOR ME, HALLOWEEN is the best holiday in the world and even beats
Christmas. I get to dress up in a costume.
I get to wear a mask. I get to go around
like every other kid with a mask and nobody thinks I look weird. Nobody takes
a second look. Nobody notices me. Nobody knows me. I wish every day could be
Halloween. We could all wear masks all the time. Then we could walk around and
get to know each other before we get to see what we looked like under the mask
When I was little, I used to wear an astronaut helmet everywhere I went. To
the playground. To the supermarket. To pick Via up from school. Even in the
middle of summer, though it was so hot my
face would sweat. I think I wore it for a couple of years, but I had to stop
wearing it when I had my eye surgery. I was about seven, I think. And then we
couldn’t find the helmet after that. Mom looked everywhere for it. She figured
that it had probably ended up in gr's attic, and she kept meaning to look for
it, but by then I had gotten used to not
wearing it. I have pictures of me in all my Halloween costumes. My first Halloween
I was a pumpkin. My second I was Tigger.
My third I was Peter pant my dad dressed up as Captain Hook). My fourth I was
Captain Hook (my dad dressed up as Peter Pan). My fifth I was an AS
My sixth I was Obi-Wan Kenobi. My seventh I was a clone trooper. My eighth I was
Darth Vader. My ninth I was the Bleeding Scream, the one that has fake blood
oozing out all over the skull mask. This year I’m going to be Boba Fett: not Boba
Fett the kid in Star Wars Episode 2 Attack of the Clones but Boba Fett the
man from Star Wars Episode five The Empire Strikes Back Mom searched everywhere for the costume
but couldn’t find one of my size, so she bought me a Jango Fett costume— —since
Jango was Boba’s dad and wore the same armor— —and then painted the armor green.
She did some other stuff to it to make it look worn, too. Anyway, it looks totally
real. Mom’s good at costumes. In home room we all talked about what we were going
to be for Halloween. Charlotte was going as Hermione from Harry Potter. Jack was
going as wolfman. I heard that Julian was going as D Jango Fett, which was a weird
coincidence. I don’t think he liked hearing that I was going as Boba Fett. On
the morning of Halloween, Via had this big crying meltdown about something.
Via’s always been so calm and cool, but this year she’s had a couple of these
kinds of fits. Dad was late for work and was like, “Via, let’s go! Let’s
go!” Usually Dad is super patient about things, but not when it comes to his
being late for work, and his yelling just stressed out Via even more, and she
started crying louder, so Mom told Dad to take me to school and that she’d deal with
Via. Then Mom kissed me goodbye quickly, before I even put on my costume, and
disappeared into Via’s room hoggy let’s
go now!” said Dad. “I have a meeting I can’t
be late for!” “I have I haven’t put my
costume on yet!” “So put it on, already 5 minutes. I’ll meet you outside.” I rushed
to my room and started to put on the Boba Fett costume, but all of a sudden I
didn’t feel like wearing it. I’m not sure why— —maybe because I had all these belts
that needed to be tightened and I needed someone’s help to put it on. Or maybe it
was because it still smelled a little like paint. All I knew was that it was a
lot of work to put the costume on, and Dad was waiting and would get super
impatient if I made him late. So, at the last minute, I threw on the Bleeding
Scream costume from last year. It was such an easy costume: just had a long
black robe and a big white mask. I yell goodbye from the door on my way out, but
Mom didn’t even hear me. “I thought you were going to Django Fett,” said Dad when
I got outside boa Fett!” “Whatever,” said Dad.
“This is a better costume anyway.” “Yeah, it’s cool,” I answered the bleeding scream WALKING
THROUGH THE halls that morning on my way to the lockers was, I have to say,
absolutely awesome. Everything was different now. I was different. Where I
usually walked with my head down, trying to avoid being seen, today I walked with
my head up, looking around. I wanted to be seen. One kid wearing the same exact
costume as mine, long white skull face oozing fake red blood, high-fived me as we passed each
other on the stairs. I have no idea who
he was, and he had no idea who I was, and
I wondered for a second if he would have
ever done that if he’d known it was me under the mask. I was starting to think
this was going to go down as one of the most awesome days in the history of my
life, but then I got The Home Room The first costume I saw as I walked inside
the door was dark cious It had one of the rubber masks that are so realistic,
with a big black hood over the head and a long black robe. I knew right away it
was Julian, of course. He must have changed his costume at the last minute
because he thought I was coming as D Jango Fett. He was talking to two mummies
who must have been Miles and Henry, and they were all kind of looking at the
door like they were waiting for someone to come through it. I knew it wasn’t a
Bleeding Scream they were looking for. It was Boba Fett. I was going to go and sit
at my usual desk, but for some reason, I don’t know why, I found myself walking
over to a desk near them, and I could hear them talking. One of the mummies was
saying: “It really does look like him.” “Like this part especially answered Julian’s
voice. He put his fingers on the cheeks and eyes of his Darth cious mask.
“Actually,” said the mummy, “what he really looks like is one of those shrunken
heads. Have you ever seen those? He looks exactly like that.” “I think he looks like
an orc.” “Oh yeah!” “If I look like that,” said the Julian voice, kind of laughing, “I
swear to God I put a hood over my face
every day.” “I’ve thought about this a lot,” said the second mummy, sounding serious,
“and I really think if I look like him, seriously, I think that I’d kill myself.”
“You would not,” answered Darth cidus yeah Yeah, for real,” insisted the same mmy I
can’t imagine looking in the mirror every day and seeing myself like that. It
would be too awful. And getting stared at all the
time.” “Then why do you hang out with him so much?” asked Darth cidus I don’t know,”
answered the mummy. “Tushman asked me to hang out with him at the beginning of
the year, and he must have told all the teachers to put us next to each other in
all our classes, or something.” The mummy shrugged. I knew the of course. I knew the
voice. I knew I wanted to run out of the class right then and there. But I stood
where I was and listen to Jack Will finish what he was
saying. “I mean, the thing is: he always follows me around. What am I supposed to
do?” “Just Stitch him,” said Julian. I don’t know what Jack answered
because I walked out of the class without anyone knowing I had been there.
My face felt like it was on fire while I walked back down the stairs. I was
sweating under my costume. And I started crying. I couldn’t keep it from happening.
The tears were so thick in my eyes I could barely see, but I couldn’t wipe
them through the mask as I walked. I was looking for a little tiny spot to
disappear into. I wanted a hole I could fall inside of: a little black hole that
would eat me up names RAT BOY. FREAK. MONSTER Freddy Krueger ET gross out Lizard face. Mutant.
I know the names they call me. I’ve been in enough playgrounds to know kids can
be mean. I know, I know, I know. I ended up
in the second floor bathroom. No one was there because first period had started
and everyone was in class. I locked the door to my stall and took off my mask
and just cried for I don’t know how long.
Then I went to the nurse’s office and told her I had a stomach ache, which was
true, because I felt like I’d been kicked in the gut. Nurse Molly called Mom and
had me lie down on the sofa next to her desk 15 minutes later, Mom was at the
door. “Sweetness,” she said, coming over to hug me. “Hi,” I mumbled. I didn’t want her to
ask anything until afterward. “You have a stomach ache?” she asked, automatically
putting her hand on my forehead to check for my temperature. “He says he feels like
throwing up,” said ner Molly, looking at me with very nice
eyes. “And I have a headache,” I whispered. “I wonder if it’s something you ate,” said
Mom, looking worried. “There’s a stomach bug going around,” said Nurse Molly. “Oh jeez said Mom,
her eyebrows going up as she shook her head. She helped me to my feet. “Should I
call a taxi or are you okay walking home?” “I can walk.” “What a brave kid!” said Nurse
Molly, patting me on the back as she walked us toward the door. “If he starts
throwing up or runs a temperature, you should call the doctor.” “Absolutely,” said
Mom, shaking Nurse Molly’s hand. “Thank you so much for taking care of him.” “My
pleasure,” answered Nurse Molly, putting her hand under my chin and tilting my
face up. “You take care of yourself, okay?” I nodded and mumbled “Thank you.” Mom and I
hug walked the whole way home. I didn’t tell her anything about what had
happened, and later when she asked me if I felt well enough to go
trick-or-treating after school, I said no.
This worried her, since she knew how much I usually loved
trick-or-treating. I heard her say to Dad on the phone: He doesn’t even have the
energy to go trick-or-treating. No, no fever at all
Well, I will if he doesn’t feel better by tomorrow. I know, poor thing Imagine his missing
Halloween.” I got out of going to school the next day, too, which was Friday. So I
had the whole weekend to think about everything. I was pretty sure I would
never go back to school again
[Music]